

ANDROID DEVELOPER

Pallippattu House , Sreekandamangalam PO, Kottayam, Kerala, Pin-686562

□ (+91) 9400 832 145 | ■ bibinpjacob91@gmail.com | ♣ https://bibinjacob.github.io/ | • bibinjacob

Summary

Software Developer with 2 years experience on building, integrating, testing and supporting Android applications.

Striving to update my knowledge and skills through continuous self learning.

Skills

Operating Systems GNU/Linux (Ubuntu), Windows, Android

Programming JAVA

Web HTML, CSS

Development Tools Android Studio, Eclipse IDE, Android SDK, DDMS, SQLyog, NetBeans, Unity

Databases MySQL, SQLite

Version Control System Git

Experience ____

GrandTrust InfoTech Ernakulam, Kerala

MOBILE APPLICATION DEVELOPER Feb. 2016 - PRESENT

• Refactoring application AsterApps.

- Develop resultanturas for gara t
- Develop new features for gerp+.
- Develop android app for queue management system QMagik.
- · Cooperating with other teams across organisation for efficient work progress.

Dieutek Developmets Ernakulam, Kerala

SOFTWARE ENGINEER Dec. 2014 - Jan. 2016

- Created Volker Motors, a service booking application.
- · Take a part of organize team processes.

Adhoc Technologies Thiruvananthapuram, Kerala

May. 2014 - Dec. 2014

Internship Trainee

- learned android programming by doing simple projects.
- · Assisted college students in their projects.

Projects

QMagik

QUEUE MANAGEMENT SYSTEM

- Involved in Analysis and Design Phase.
- Playing a major role in android app development.
- · Working with backend team to implement features in android app.
- http://www.qmagik.com/

AsterApps

APPOINTMENT MANAGEMENT SYSTEM FOR CONSULTING DOCTORS

- · Refactored application.
- https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.dieutek.volkermotor

gerp+

ERP SUITE SPECIALLY DESIGNED FOR LATEX BASED PRODUCT MANUFACTURING INDUSTRY

- Involved in Analysis and Design Phase.
- Played a major role in android app development.
- Released Application in Google Play.
- http://www.thegti.com/Content.aspx?CV=7

Volker Motors

SERVICE BOOKING APPLICATION WITH FEATURES LIKE INSURANCE REMAINDER, SERVICE REMAINDER

- Involved in Analysis and Design Phase.
- Developed the whole app.
- Implemented server application using JSON-REST services.
- Published Application on Google Play.
- https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.dieutek.volkermotor

KoKo Fly

2D GAME WITH FLIGHT OF A BIRD AS THE MAIN PERSPECTIVE

- Develped using Unity 5.1.2
- Published Application on Google Play.
- https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.Dieutek.kokofly

Education

Lourdes Matha College of Science and Technology

Kerala University
Mar. 2009 - 2013

B.Tech in Computer Science and Engineering

• Organised inter college Computer Science fest